

1607- 85 E Liberty St Toronto, ON M6K 3R4 (647) 821-1942 portfolio <u>abdielmi.ca</u>
github <u>github.com/elmi-</u>
linkedin <u>linkedin.com/in/elmi-</u>
email abdi.elmi@rocketmail.com

PROFILE

Full Stack Developer with nearly a decade's worth of experience within the software industry. I am looking to continue my career within software as a Full Stack Developer! In addition to my skills and experiences as a web developer, my experience as a Senior Business Intelligence Developer provides me with the experience of working with clients and managing large projects.

EXPERIENCE

Student Mentor MARCH 2022 - JULY 2022

<u>Lighthouse Labs</u>

Vancouver, BC

 Mentored and assisted Lighthouse Labs Web Development students with finding programming bugs and resolving technical issues

• Helped refactor students' code for simplicity and efficiency

Business Intelligence Developer

JANUARY 2019 - MARCH 2021

Centre for Addiction and Mental Health (CAMH)

Toronto, ON

- Worked as Senior Business Intelligence Developer building BI solutions for teams/departments throughout the hospital
- Effectively coded end-to-end software solutions for departments using Dundas BI, including and not limited to developing the current platform used by the Schizophrenia department
- Led the team in implementing the <u>COVID-19 National Survey Dashboard</u>
- Began the overseeing of transitioning the platform from Dundas BI to Tableau

Technical Summary: Dundas BI, SQL Server, C#, JavaScript, Microsoft Excel, Tableau

Senior Business Intelligence Consultant

APRIL 2016 - JANUARY 2019

Dundas Data Visualization Inc

Toronto, ON

- Worked with business analysts and solution architects to gather requirements and provide effort/cost estimates for BI/Dashboard solution development work
- Made recommendations and strategies for BI solutions based on customer requirements
- Designed, developed, tested, implemented and supported BI solutions using Dundas BI and other software platforms to satisfy business requirements
- In addition to creating BI/Dashboard solutions, I was in charge of also providing training using Dundas BI

Technical Summary: Dundas BI, SQL Server, SSRS (OLAP), IBM DB2, C#, CSS3, HTML5, JQuery, JavaScript, Microsoft Excel

Junior Business Analyst, Support Associate

JULY 2015 - APRIL 2016

Dundas Data Visualization Inc

Toronto, ON

- Helped end users answer their questions/problems regarding the use of Dundas BI
- Provided development support using Dundas BI for Fortune 500 companies and supported clients on Microsoft technologies including ASP.NET, IIS, SharePoint and SQL Server Analysis Services

Technical Summary: Dundas Bl, SQL Server, SSRS (OLAP), C#, CSS3, HTML5, JQuery, JavaScript, Microsoft Excel

Junior Web Developer

APRIL 2014 - APRIL 2015

Brushfire North Inc

Toronto, ON

- Junior developer with Brushfire North Inc, working with ASP.NET (both MVC and Web Forms)
- Worked both as a back-end developer and front-end developer for the company, focusing 60% of my time as a front-end developer
- The company worked closely with Agility CMS for their clients. In addition to being a developer, I did design work, producing PSD mockups for desktop and mobile projects

Technical Summary: ASP.NET MVC 4, C#, CSS3, HTML5, JQuery, JavaScript, TFS, SVN, Adobe PhotoShop CC 2014, JIRA

PROJECTS

The Office Quiz

https://github.com/elmi-/office-quiz

Full-stack project built on a React front-end and Node back-end using officeapi.dev API Try and test your Office knowledge, https://the-office-quiz.herokuapp.com/

Fantasy Radar

https://github.com/elmi-/FantasyRadar

Web app that scraps Basketball-Reference and fetches latest news for users and notifies users via text messages using Twilio API, all built with Ruby on Rails

Scheduler

https://github.com/elmi-/scheduler

Scheduling application used for booking interviews, that is dynamically rendered using React! Data is persisted by an API server using a PostgreSQL database

TinyApp

https://github.com/elmi-/tinyapp

TinyApp is a full stack web application built with Node and Express that allows users to shorten long URLs (à la bit.ly).

EDUCATION

| Web Development Bootcamp | OCTOBER 2021 - JANUARY 2022 |
|-----------------------------------|-----------------------------|
| Lighthouse Labs | Vancouver, BC |
| Computer Programming and Analysis | JANUARY 2012 - APRIL 2014 |
| George Brown College | Toronto, ON |